<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 06-Mar-13 5:44:57 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Description tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WATPHRAKAEW">
			<Text>Wat Phra Kaew</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Help tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_WATPHRAKAEW_HELP">
			<Text>+2 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science from every Shrine, Temple, Monastery, Cathedral, Mosque and Pagoda.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Quote tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_WATPHRAKAEW_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"If you're respectful by habit, constantly honoring the worthy, four things increase: long life, beauty, happiness, strength." [NEWLINE]- The Buddha[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pedia tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_WATPHRAKAEW_PEDIA">
			<Text>Wat Phra Kaew or the Temple of the Emerald Buddha (officially known as Wat Phra Sri Rattana Satsadaram) is regarded as the most important Buddhist temple in Thailand. Located in the historic centre of Bangkok, within the grounds of the Grand Palace, it enshrines Phra Kaew Morakot (the Emerald Buddha), the highly revered Buddha image meticulously carved from a single block of jade. The Emerald Buddha (Phra Putta Maha Mani Ratana Patimakorn) is a Buddha image in the meditating position in the style of the Lanna school of the north, dating from the 15th century AD.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Raised high on a series of platforms, no one is allowed near the Buddha except the King. A seasonal cloak, changed three times a year to correspond to the summer, winter, and rainy season covers the statue. A very important ritual, the changing of the robes is performed only by the King to bring good fortune to the country during each season.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The construction of the temple started when King Buddha Yodfa Chulaloke (Rama I) moved the capital from Thonburi to Bangkok in 1785. Unlike other temples, it does not contain living quarters for monks; rather, it has only elaborately decorated holy buildings, statues, and pagodas. The main building is the central 'ubosot' (ordination hall), which houses the Emerald Buddha.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>