<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/26/2013 9:33:44 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SELJUQ_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_SELJUQ_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				The Seljuq Empire controlled a vast area stretching from the Hindu Kush to eastern Anatolia and from Central Asia to the Persian Gulf. From their homelands near the Aral sea, the Seljuqs advanced first into Khorasan and then into mainland Persia before eventually conquering eastern Anatolia. The Seljuq empire was founded by Tughril Beg in 1037 after the efforts by the founder of the Seljuq dynasty, Seljuk Bey, in the first quarter of the 11th century. Seljuk Bey's father was in a higher position in the Oghuz Yabgu State, and he gave his name to both the state and the dynasty. The Seljuqs united the fractured political scene of the Eastern Islamic world and played a key role in the first and second crusades. Highly Persianized in culture and language, the Seljuqs also played an important role in the development of the Turko-Persian tradition, even exporting Persian culture to Anatolia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Tughril was the grandson of Seljuq and brother of Chaghri, under whom the Seljuks wrested an empire from the Ghaznavids. Initially the Seljuqs were repulsed by Mahmud and retired to Khwarezm, but Tughril and Chaghri led them to capture Merv and Nishapur (1037). In 1040 at the Battle of Dandanaqan, they decisively defeated Mas'ud I of the Ghaznavids, forcing him to abandon most of his western territories to the Seljuqs. In 1055, Tughril captured Baghdad from the Shi'a Buyids under a commission from the Abbassids. Alp Arslan, the son of Chaghri Beg, expanded significantly upon Tughril's holdings by adding Armenia and Georgia in 1064 and invading the Byzantine Empire in 1068, from which he annexed almost all of Anatolia. Under Alp Arslan's successor, Malik Shah, and his two Persian viziers, Nizam al-Mulk and Taj al-Mulk, the Seljuq state expanded in various directions, to the former Iranian border of the days before the Arab invasion, so that it soon bordered China in the East and the Byzantines in the West. The reign of Malik Shah was reckoned the golden age of "Great Seljuq". When Malikshāh I died in 1092, the empire split as his brother and four sons quarrelled over the apportioning of the empire among themselves. In 1118, the third son Ahmad Sanjar took over the empire. The empire fractured and the seperate territories fell to the First and Second crusades, sometimes even allying with them to defeat other territories formerly part of the Seljuq Empire. Ahmad Sanjar had to contend with the revolts of Qarakhanids in Transoxiana, Ghorids in Afghanistan and Qarluks in modern Kyrghyzstan, as well as the nomadic Kara-Khitais who invaded the East and captured the Eastern Qarakhanid state. For a brief period, Togrul III was the Sultan of all Seljuq except for Anatolia. Eventually, the Empire collapsed.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Alp Arslan was the second Sultan of the Seljuq Empire and great-grandson of Seljuq, the eponymous founder of the dynasty. His real name was Muhammad bin Dawud Chaghri, and for his military prowess, personal valour, and fighting skills he obtained the name Alp Arslan, which means "Heroic Lion" in Turkish.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Alp Arslan succeeded his father Cagri Bey as governor of Khorasan in 1059. His uncle Tughril died and was succeeded by Suleiman, Arslan's brother. Arslan and his uncle Kutalmish both contested this succession. Arslan defeated Kutalmish for the throne and succeeded on 27 April 1064 as sultan of Great Seljuq, thus becoming sole monarch of Persia from the river Oxus to the Tigris. In consolidating his empire and subduing contending factions, Arslan was ably assisted by Nizam al-Mulk, his vizier, and one of the most eminent statesmen in early Muslim history. With peace and security established in his dominions, Arslan convoked an assembly of the states and declared his son Malik Shah I his heir and successor. With the hope of capturing Caesarea Mazaca, the capital of Cappadocia, he placed himself at the head of the Turkish cavalry, crossed the Euphrates, and entered and invaded the city. Along with Nizam al-Mulk, he then marched into Armenia and Georgia, which he conquered in 1064. After numerous battles, Alp Arslan was victorious in the Battle of Manzikert in 1071. This victory turned the tide and the Seljuqs were able to invade the rest of Anatolia. Alp Arslan's victories changed the balance in near Asia completely in favour of the Seljuq Turks and Sunni Muslims. While the Byzantine Empire was to continue for nearly four more centuries, and the Crusades would contest the issue for some time, the victory at Manzikert signalled the beginning of Turkish ascendancy in Anatolia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After Manzikert, the dominion of Alp Arslan extended over much of western Asia. He soon prepared to march for the conquest of Turkestan, the original seat of his ancestors. With a powerful army he advanced to the banks of the Oxus. Before he could pass the river with safety, however, it was necessary to subdue certain fortresses, one of which was for several days vigorously defended by the governor, Yussuf el-Harezmi, a Khwarezmian. He was obliged to surrender, however, and was carried as a prisoner before the sultan, who condemned him to death. Yussuf, in desperation, drew his dagger and rushed upon the sultan. Alp Arslan, who took great pride in his reputation as the foremost archer of his time, motioned to his guards not to interfere. He drew his bow, but his foot slipped, the arrow glanced aside, and he received the assassin's dagger in his breast. Alp Arslan died from this wound four days later, on 25 November 1072, in his 42nd year, and he was taken to Merv to be buried next to his father, Chaghri Beg.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_LIVED">
			<Text>1029 - 1072 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_NAME">
			<Text>Alp Arslan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of the Seljuqs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Heroic Lion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ALP_ARSLAN_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Sultan of the Seljuq Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_KHORASAN_FIEFDOM">
			<Text>Upgrade units at half [ICON_GOLD] cost. +20% [ICON_RANGE_STRENGTH] Ranged Combat Strength for Ranged units. Gain a [ICON_RESEARCH] Tech boost towards any killed unit's required Technology.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_KHORASAN_FIEFDOM_SHORT">
			<Text>Khorasan Fiefdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALP_ARSLAN_FIRST_GREETING_1">
			<Text>What? Who are you? I don't have a lot of time: there are enemies to be subdued.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALP_ARSLAN_FIRST_GREETING_2">
			<Text>They call me Sultan Alp Arslan for my military prowess and personal valour. Do you have a similar title?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALP_ARSLAN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You succeeded in conquering a mighty empire! Now nothing is in your way.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALP_ARSLAN_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>The empire will strike back!</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>