<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 4/13/2014 1:47:48 AM -->
<GameData>
		<Language_en_US>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_ALGERIA_HEADING_1">
				<Text>History</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DJSH_ALGERIA_TEXT_1">
				<Text>Neolithic civilization (animal domestication and agriculture) developed in the Saharan and Mediterranean Maghrib between 6000 and 2000 BC. This life, richly depicted in the Tassili n'Ajjer paintings, predominated in Algeria until the classical period. The amalgam of peoples of North Africa coalesced eventually into a distinct native population that came to be called Berbers, who are the indigenous peoples of northern Africa. From their principal center of power at Carthage, the Carthaginians expanded and established small settlements along the North African coast; by 600 BC, a Phoenician presence existed at Tipasa, east of Cherchell, Hippo Regius (modern Annaba) and Rusicade (modern Skikda). These settlements served as market towns as well as anchorages. As Carthaginian power grew, its impact on the indigenous population increased dramatically. Berber civilization was already at a stage in which agriculture, manufacturing, trade, and political organization supported several states. Trade links between Carthage and the Berbers in the interior grew, but territorial expansion also resulted in the enslavement or military recruitment of some Berbers and in the extraction of tribute from others. The Carthaginian state declined because of successive defeats by the Romans in the Punic Wars. By the 2nd century BC, several large but loosely administered Berber kingdoms had emerged. Two of them were established in Numidia, behind the coastal areas controlled by Carthage. West of Numidia lay Mauretania. The high point of Berber civilization, unequaled until the coming of the Almohads and Almoravids more than a millennium later, was reached during the reign of Massinissa in the 2nd century BC. After Masinissa's death in 148 BC, the Berber kingdoms were divided and reunited several times. Massinissa's line survived until 24 AD, when the remaining Berber territory was annexed to the Roman Empire. For several centuries Algeria was ruled by the Romans, who founded many colonies in the region. The Vandals of Geiseric moved into North Africa in 429, and by 435 controlled coastal Numidia. The region was later recaptured by the Eastern Roman Empire, which ruled it until the Muslim Conquest in the 7th century. Muslim Arabs conquered Algeria in the mid-7th century and a large number of locals converted to the new faith. After the fall of the Umayyad Arab Dynasty in 751, numerous local Berber dynasties emerged, including the Aghlabids, Almohads, Abdalwadid, Zirids, Rustamids, Hammadids, Almoravids and the Fatimids. In the 16th century the region was conquered by the Ottoman Empire, but it lost effective influence in 1710 after the dey persuaded the sultan to recognize him and his successors as regent of Algiers. The French invaded and captured Algiers in 1830. Abdelkader El Djezairi, recognized as Emir, fiercely resisted the French invasion until his eventual surrender in 1847. Algeria gained independence in 1962. </Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_HEADING_1">
				<Text>General Information</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_TEXT_1">
				<Text>Abdelkader ibn Muhieddine, known as the Emir Abdelkader or Abdelkader El Djezairi, was an Algerian religious and military leader who led a struggle against the French colonial invasion in the mid-19th century. An Islamic scholar and Sufi who unexpectedly found himself leading a military campaign, he built up a collection of Algerian tribesmen that for many years successfully held out against one of the most advanced armies in Europe. His consistent regard for what would now be called human rights, especially as regards his Christian opponents, drew widespread admiration, and a crucial intervention to save the Christian community of Damascus from a massacre in 1860 brought honours and awards from around the world. Within Algeria, his efforts to unite the country against foreign invaders saw him hailed as the "modern Jugurtha," and his ability to combine religious and political authority has led to his being acclaimed as the "Saint among the Princes, the Prince among the Saints".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He grew up in his father's zawiya, which by the early nineteenth century had become the centre of a thriving community on the banks of the Oued al-Hammam river. Like other students, he received a traditional education in theology, jurisprudence and grammar; it was said that could read and write by the age of five. In 1830, Algeria was invaded by France; French colonial domination over Algeria eventually supplanted domination by the Ottoman Empire and the Koulouglis. There was a lot of pent-up resentment against the Ottomans when the French arrived, and due to numerous rebellions in the early 19th century, the Algerians could not oppose the French at all initially. When the French Africa Army reached Oran in January 1831, Abdelkader's father was asked to lead a harassment campaign against them; Muhieddine called for a jihad and he and his son were among those involved in early attacks below the walls of the city. It was at this point that Abdelkader came to the fore. At a meeting of the western tribes in the autumn of 1832, he was elected Emir, or Commander of the Faithful (following his father's refusal of the position on the grounds that he was too old). Within a year, through a combination of punitive raids and careful politics, Abdelkader had succeeded in uniting the tribes in the region and in reestablishing security – his area of influence now covered the entire Province of Oran. After several treaties, victories and losses, Abdelkader won control of all of Oran and extended his reach to the neighbouring province of Titteri and beyond. The period of peace following the Treaty of Tafna benefited both sides, and the Emir Abdelkader took the opportunity to consolidate a new functional state, with a capital in Tagdemt. This state was broadly theocratic, with even the currency called muhammadiyya, after the Prophet. Peace with France was broken in 1839 and the struggle went in Abdelkader's favor until 1842. Abdelkader eventually had to surrender in 1847. Abdelkader and his family and followers were detained in France. Eventually, on 16 October 1852, Abdelkader was released by the President and given an annual pension of 100 000 francs on taking an oath never again to disturb Algeria. He then took up residence in Bursa, today's Turkey, moving in 1855 to Amara District in Damascus. In July 1860, conflict between the Druze and Maronites of Mount Lebanon spread to Damascus, and local Druze attacked the Christian quarter, killing over 3,000 people. Abdelkader had previously warned the French consul as well as the Council of Damascus that violence was imminent; when it finally broke out, he sheltered large numbers of Christians, including the heads of several foreign consulates as well as religious groups such as the Sisters of Mercy, in the safety of his house.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_LIVED">
				<Text>1808 - 1883 AD</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_NAME">
				<Text>Abdelkader El Djezairi</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_SUBTITLE">
				<Text>Leader of Algeria</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_TITLES_1">
				<Text>Emir</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_TITLES_2">
				<Text>Shaykh</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_DJSH_ALGERIA_SAINT_AMONG_PRINCES">
				<Text>Cities gain extra [ICON_STRENGTH] Defensive Combat Strength based on total [ICON_PEACE] Faith output per turn. Strategic Resources on Desert provide double quantity.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_DJSH_ALGERIA_SAINT_AMONG_PRINCES_SHORT">
				<Text>Saint Among the Princes</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_FIRST_GREETING_1">
				<Text>Greetings, stranger. I come here for my peace. What brings you here?</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_FIRST_GREETING_2">
				<Text>Welcome to Algeria. Let us put our religious differences aside for a moment and talk.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_DEFEATED_1">
				<Text>Fine, we submit. No longer will I waste the lives of others.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ABDELKADER_EL_DJEZAIRI_DEFEATED_2">
				<Text>I can no longer witness your cruelty and ignorance. Begone.</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_DIVAN">
				<Text>Bey|Beys</Text>
				<Plurality>1|2</Plurality>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_DIVAN_TITLE">
				<Text>Dey Points:</Text>
			</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPECIALIST_DIVAN_SLOTS">
				<Text>Bey Slots:</Text>
			</Row>
		</Language_en_US>
</GameData>