<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						State
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_DESC">
			<Text>Kingdom of Israel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Israel</Text>
			<Plurality>1</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Israel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_ISRAEL_MOD_LS">
			<Text>Israel</Text>
			<Plurality>1</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_ISRAEL_LS_MOD_HEADING_1">
			<Text>The Jewish Kingdom</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_ISRAEL_LS_MOD_TEXT_1">
			<Text>According to Jewish tradition, Jewish ancestry is traced back to the Biblical patriarchs Abraham, Isaac and Jacob, who lived in Canaan around the 18th century BCE. Jacob and his family migrated to Ancient Egypt after being invited to live with Joseph (who rose to the rank of Pharaoh's Vizier) in the Land of Goshen region by Pharaoh himself. Their descendants were later enslaved until the Exodus led by Moses, which is commonly dated to the 13th century BCE. Historically, Jews have descended mostly from the tribes of Judah and Simeon, and partially from the tribes of Benjamin and Levi, who had all together formed the ancient Kingdom of Judah (alongside the remnants of the Northern Kingdom of Israel who migrated to their Southern counterpart and assimilated there). A closely related group is the Samaritans, who claim descent from the Israelite tribes of Ephraim and Manasseh, while according to the Bible their origin is in the people brought to Israel by the Neo-Assyrian Empire and some Cohanim (Jewish priests) who taught them how to worship the "native God".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The United Monarchy is the name given to the Israelite kingdom of Israel and Judah, during the reigns of Saul, David and Solomon, known primarily from the Hebrew Bible. This is traditionally dated between 1020 and 930 BCE. On the succession of Solomon's son, Rehoboam, in c. 930 BCE the biblical account reports that the country split into two kingdoms; the Kingdom of Israel (including the cities of Shechem and Samaria) in the north and the Kingdom of Judah (containing Jerusalem) in the south. However, modern scholarship has challenged the biblical account using both literary and archaeological evidence, leading to questions over the historicity of some or all of the account.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_ISRAEL_LS_MOD_HEADING_2">
			<Text>History of the United Monarchy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_ISRAEL_LS_MOD_TEXT_2">
			<Text>According to the Book of Judges, the Israelite tribes previously lived as a confederation under ad hoc charismatic leaders called Judges. Abimelech was the first to be declared king by the men of Shechem and the house of Millo, and reigned over Israel for three years before he was killed during the Battle of Thebez.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]According to the biblical account, the united monarchy was formed when there was a large popular expression in favour of introducing a king to rule over the previously decentralised Israelite tribal confederacy. Increasing pressure from the Philistines and other neighboring tribes is said by the Bible to have forced the Israelites to unite as a more singular state when Samuel anointed Saul from the tribe of Benjamin as the first king. The Bible treats the notion of kingship as having been an anathema at the time, it being seen as one man put in a position of reverence and power, which in their faith was reserved for God.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]According to the Second Book of Samuel, due to his disobedience to God, Saul's reign was curtailed and his kingdom given to another dynasty. The Masoretic Text says that Saul ruled for only two years, although this is improbable. The Bible portrays Saul as having died in battle against the Philistines. David and Saul had earlier become bitter enemies, at least from Saul's point of view, although the sources describe Jonathan, Saul's son, and Michal, Saul's daughter, as assisting David to escape Saul, ultimately leading to brief reconciliation before Saul's death.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Saul's heir, Ishbaal, took over rulership of Israel but, according to Samuel, ruled for only two years before he was assassinated. David, who had become king of Judah only, ended the conspiracy, and was appointed king of Israel in Ishbaal's place. A number of textual critics and biblical scholars have suggested that David was actually responsible for the assassination, and David's innocence was a later invention to legitimize his actions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Israel rebels, according to Samuel, and appoints David's son Absalom as their new king. The Bible then describes Israel as taking over Judah and ultimately forcing David into exile east of the Jordan. According to the increasing majority of archaeologists, this isn't so much a case of rebellion by Israel against a mighty kingdom, but more a case of Israel re-asserting its authority over a poor, rural, sparsely populated, backwater. This section of the biblical text, and the bulk of the remainder of the Books of Samuel, is thought by textual critics to belong to a single large source known as the Court History of David. Although reflecting the political bias of the later kingdom of Judah after Israel's destruction, the source is somewhat more neutral than the pro and anti monarchical sources that form earlier parts of the text. Israel and Judah are portrayed in this source as quite distinct kingdoms.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Eventually, according to the Book of Samuel, David launches a counter-attack, and wins, although with the loss of Absalom. After having retaken Judah, as well as asserted control over Israel, David returns to the west of the Jordan, although he continues to suffer a number of rebellions by Israel, successfully suppressing each one.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was David who, following the civil war with Saul, creates a strong and unified Israelite monarchy, reigning from c. 1000-961 BCE. Solomon, David's successor, maintained the unified monarchy, c. 961-922. David, the third King of Israel, established Jerusalem as its national capital in 1006 BCE. Before then, Hebron had been the capital of David's Judah and Mahanaim of Ish-baal's Israel, and before that Gibeah had been the capital of the United Monarchy under Saul. David embarked on successful military campaigns against Israel's enemies, and defeated nearby regional entities such as the Philistines, thus creating secure borders for Israel. Under David, Israel grew into a regional power. Under the House of David, the United Monarchy achieved prosperity and superiority over its neighbours.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]David embarked on successful military campaigns against Judah's and Israel's enemies, and defeated bitter foes such as the Philistines, thus creating secure borders. Under King David, Israel grew from Kingdom to Empire, and its sphere of influence – militarily and politically – in the Middle East expanded greatly, controlling a number of weaker client states like Philistia, Moab, Edom, Ammon, with a number of Aramaean city-states (Aram-Zobah and Aram-Damascus) becoming vassal states; the imperial border stretched from the Mediterranean Sea to the Arabian Desert, from the Red Sea to the Euphrates River. According to the biblical account, the empire had a large land area. Some modern archaeologists believe that the area under the control of Judah and Israel in this era, excluding the Phoenician territories on the shore of the Mediterranean, did not exceed 34,000 square kilometres (13,000 sq mi); of these, the kingdom of Israel encompassed about 24,000 square kilometres (9,300 sq mi).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]David was succeeded on his death by his son, Solomon, who obtained the kingdom in a somewhat disreputable manner from the rival claimant, his elder brother Adonijah, whom he later had killed. Living up to his name (peace), the rule of Solomon was one in which the nation knew unprecedented peace. Under Solomon, the United Monarchy experienced a period of peace and prosperity, and cultural development. Much public building took place, including the First Temple in Jerusalem. [NEWLINE][NEWLINESolomon is said to have rebuilt a number of major cities, including Megiddo, Hazor, and Gezer; these have been excavated and some scholars attributed elements of the archaeological remains, such as six chambered gates and ashlar palaces, to this building programme. However later excavation teams at Meggido have made it clear that these structures are from different and later time periods. Yigael Yadin subsequently concluded that the stables that were once believed to have served the vast collection of horses that Solomon is believed to have kept, were actually built by King Ahab in the 9th century BCE.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following Solomon's death in c. 926 BCE, tensions between the northern part of Israel containing the ten northern tribes, and the southern section dominated by Jerusalem and the southern tribes reached boiling point. When Solomon's successor Rehoboam dealt tactlessly with economic complaints of the northern tribes, in about 930 BCE (there are difference of opinion as to the actual year) the united Kingdom of Israel and Judah split into two kingdoms: the northern Kingdom of Israel (Samaria), which included the cities of Shechem and Samaria, and the southern Kingdom of Judah, which contained Jerusalem; with most of the non-Israelite provinces achieving independence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Kingdom of Israel (or Northern Kingdom, or Samaria) existed as an independent state until 722 BCE when it was conquered by the Assyrian Empire, while the Kingdom of Judah (or Southern Kingdom) existed as an independent state until 586 BCE when it was conquered by the Babylonian Empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- City Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_1">
			<Text>Yerushalayim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_2">
			<Text>Samaria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_3">
			<Text>Hebron</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_4">
			<Text>Jerash</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_5">
			<Text>Lachish</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_6">
			<Text>Beersheba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_7">
			<Text>Jericho</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_8">
			<Text>Jaffa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_9">
			<Text>Shechem</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_10">
			<Text>Beit El</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_11">
			<Text>Hesbon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_12">
			<Text>Arad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_13">
			<Text>Debir</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_14">
			<Text>Laquis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_15">
			<Text>Ekron</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_16">
			<Text>Tirza</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_17">
			<Text>Megiddo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_18">
			<Text>Kamon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_19">
			<Text>Dor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_20">
			<Text>Mefaat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_21">
			<Text>Gibeton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_22">
			<Text>Elteke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_23">
			<Text>Estemoa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_24">
			<Text>Beser</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_25">
			<Text>Zafon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_26">
			<Text>Edrei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_27">
			<Text>Jezreel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_28">
			<Text>Silo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_29">
			<Text>Piraton</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_0">
			<Text>Aaron</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_1">
			<Text>Eleazar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_2">
			<Text>Jarah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_3">
			<Text>Penuel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_4">
			<Text>Zacchaeus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_5">
			<Text>Abiah</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_6">
			<Text>Edna</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_7">
			<Text>Jedidah</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_8">
			<Text>Persis</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_9">
			<Text>Zipporah</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Leader
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DESC">
			<Text>Solomon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_LIVED">
			<Text>1011 - 931 BCE</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_NAME">
			<Text>Solomon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_TITLES_1">
			<Text>The Peaceful</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_TEXT_1">
			<Text>According to the biblical First Book of Kings, when David was old, "he could not get warm." "So they sought for a beautiful young woman throughout all the territory of Israel, and found Abishag the Shunammite, and brought her to the king. The young woman was very beautiful, and she was of service to the king and attended to him, but the king knew her not." While David was in this state, his fourth son Adonijah, heir apparent to the throne after the death of his elder brothers Amnon and Absalom, acted to have himself declared king, but Bathsheba, a wife of David and Solomon's mother, along with the prophet Nathan, convinced David to proclaim Solomon king. Adonijah fled and took refuge at the altar, and received pardon for his conduct from Solomon on the condition that he show himself "a worthy man".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Adonijah asked to marry Abishag the Shunammite, but Solomon disallowed that, although Bathsheba now pleaded on Adonijah's behalf. He was then seized and put to death (1 Kings 2:13-25). As made clear in the earlier story of Absalom's rebellion, to possess the royal harem was in this society tantamount to claiming the throne; this applied even to a woman who had shared the bed of a king advanced in age, though she had no intimate relations with King David.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]David's general Joab was killed, in accord with David's deathbed request to Solomon, because he had killed generals Abner and Amasa during a peace. David's priest Abiathar was exiled by Solomon because he had sided with Adonijah. Abiathar is a descendent of Eli, which has important prophetic significance. Shimei was confined to Jerusalem and killed three years later, when he went to Gath to retrieve some runaway servants, in part because he had cursed David when David's son Absalom rebelled against David.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Solomon is remembered in the texts for his great wisdom. In one account, known as the Judgment of Solomon, two women came before Solomon to resolve a quarrel over which was the true mother of a baby. When Solomon suggested they should divide the living child in two with a sword, one woman said she would rather give up the child than see it killed. Solomon then declared the woman who showed compassion to be the true mother, and gave the baby to her.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Solomon is also noted as one of many authors of wisdom literature. The apocryphal/deuterocanonical Wisdom of Solomon, along with the Book of Sirach, "are the familiar personalities and the events of Israel's history combined with the wisdom tradition. Much of this literature, however, is attributed to Solomon." Solomon became a favorite author and contributor of different kinds of wisdom literature, "including not only the collections of Proverbs, but also of Ecclesiastes and the Song of Solomon and the later apocryphal book the Wisdom of Solomon."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]According to the Bible, Solomon had 700 wives and 300 concubines. The wives are described as foreign princesses, including Pharaoh's daughter and women of Moab, Ammon, Sidon and of the Hittites. These wives are depicted as leading Solomon away from Yahweh toward idolatry. The only wife mentioned by name is Naamah, who is described as the Ammonite. She was the mother of Solomon's successor, Rehoboam.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In a brief, unelaborated, and enigmatic passage, the Hebrew Bible describes how the fame of Solomon's wisdom and wealth spread far and wide, so much so that the queen of Sheba decided that she should meet him. The queen is described as visiting with a number of gifts including gold, spices and precious stones. When Solomon gave her "all her desire, whatsoever she asked," she left satisfied. Whether the passage is simply to provide a brief token, foreign witness of Solomon's wealth and wisdom, or whether there is meant to be something more significant to the queen's visit is unknown; nevertheless the visit of the Queen of Sheba has become the subject of numerous stories.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]An Ethiopian account from the 14th century (Kebra Nagast) maintains that the Queen of Sheba had sexual relations with King Solomon (of which the Biblical and Quranic accounts give no hint) and gave birth by the Mai Bella stream in the province of Hamasien, Eritrea. The Ethiopian tradition has a detailed account of the affair. The child was a son who went on to become Menelik I, King of Axum, and founded a dynasty that would reign as the first Jewish, then Christian Empire of Ethiopia for 2900+ years (less one usurpation episode, an interval of c. 133 years until a legitimate male heir regained the crown) until Haile Selassie was overthrown in 1974. Menelik was said to be a practicing Jew who was given a replica of the Ark of the Covenant by King Solomon; and, moreover, that the original was switched and went to Axum with him and his mother, and is still there, guarded by a single priest charged with caring for the artifact as his life's task. The claim of such a lineage and of possession of the Ark has been an important source of legitimacy and prestige for the Ethiopian monarchy throughout the many centuries of its existence, and had important and lasting effects on Ethiopian culture as a whole. The Ethiopian government and church deny all requests to view the alleged ark.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]According to 1 Kings 11:4 Solomon's "wives turned his heart after other gods", their own national deities, to whom Solomon built temples, thus incurring divine anger and retribution in the form of the division of the kingdom after Solomon's death. 1 Kings 11 describes Solomon's descent into idolatry, particularly his turning after Ashtoreth, the goddess of the Sidonians, and after Milcom, the abomination of the Ammonites. In Deuteronomy 17:16–17, a king is commanded not to multiply horses or wives, neither greatly multiply to himself gold or silver. Solomon sins in all three of these areas. Solomon collects 666 talents of gold each year (1 Kings 10:14), a huge amount of money for a small nation like Israel. Solomon gathers a large number of horses and chariots and even brings in horses from Egypt. Just as Deuteronomy 17 warns, collecting horses and chariots takes Israel back to Egypt. Finally, Solomon marries foreign women, and these women turn Solomon to other gods.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]"And the Lord was angry with Solomon, because his heart had turned away from the Lord, the God of Israel, who had appeared to him twice and had commanded him concerning this thing, that he should not go after other gods. But he did not keep what the Lord commanded. Therefore the Lord said to Solomon, "Since this has been your practice and you have not kept my covenant and my statutes that I have commanded you, I will surely tear the kingdom from you and will give it to your servant. Yet for the sake of David your father I will not do it in your days, but I will tear it out of the hand of your son. However, I will not tear away all the kingdom, but I will give one tribe to your son, for the sake of David my servant and for the sake of Jerusalem that I have chosen."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Near the end of his life, Solomon was forced to contend with several enemies, including Hadad of Edom, Rezon of Zobah, and one of his officials named Jeroboam who was from the tribe of Ephraim. The United Monarchy breaks up, with Jeroboam ruling over the northern Kingdom of Israel and Rehoboam ruling the Kingdom of Judah to the south. According to the Hebrew Bible, Solomon died of natural causes at around 80 years of age.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_TEXT">
			<Text>Great and wise Solomon, King of Israel and the son of David. You were the leader of Jewish people, ruling over a shortlived Empire in the Chosen Land, before your people would once again become wanders. Yet Babylon has fallen, Alexander ended the rules of Persians, Rome grew in power and fell, the crusaders were defeated, and still your nation has survived. The Jewish people have shown the world a strength of culture and tradition, their religion and beliefs standing strong against the many who sought to destroy them. After three thousand years, your nation has proven to be one of the most tenacious in history, carving out a place for themselves like the rain wears away at the rock.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]King Solomon, the time has come to reign once again. Shall you build great temples and bring peace to your people? Will your divine wisdom carve ought an empire of art and learning? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						Diplomacy
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Solomon, King of the Chosen People. If you seek justice or advice, know that you had found them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Greetings, traveller. Only through peace will our nations rise in power and wealth. Let our descedants not be ashamed about the things we have done.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>The Lord works in mysterious ways to place you on the throne of Israel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>Is this how my peaceful reign ends? In a river of blood and suffering...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>If you like it so much here you should think about converting.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Ah, there you are. I was told a dark and malign presence had fallen upon my court.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>May you know peace, friend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>No matter how many cities you build, how many walls you raise, I need only blow the scared horns and they shall come crumbling down before me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>I take issue with your expansionism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>The heart of the sinful is worth naught. None shall mourn your passing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DENOUNCE_2">
			<Text>You have chosen to make an enemy of the Chosen People. May your reign come to a swift and unexpected end.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>The wise in heart will receive teaching, but a fast talking fool will become nothing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_2">
			<Text>Your sinful tongue must be stopped.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- General Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} is a sinful wretch. An unholy man cannot stand before a righteous army, am I right?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_2">
			<Text>The sins of {1_PlayerName:textkey} are many, a war with them is surely justified?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_COOP_WAR_TIME_1">
			<Text>As we agreed, the heretic - {1_PlayerName:textkey} - must be stopped.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>I would be honoured for you to call me brother! May this era of peace stretch on forever.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_2">
			<Text>Let peace reign between us, so that we may more effectively pursue our victory conditions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention thay you have a large number of Units near my borders. God gave me this land, and only God can take it away.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_1">
			<Text>Those who are right with God are remembered with honor, but the name of the sinful will waste away.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_2">
			<Text>You're coming dangerously close to provoking a few plagues.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_3">
			<Text>A holy man must obey many rules, for God has no mercy. I would make sure your things in order.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_4">
			<Text>Now that you have provoked Him, a swift and awe-inspiring death is all you can look forward to.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>I could take out your whole armed forces with a division of shepherd boys!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_1">
			<Text>The writing's on the wall for you. By wall I mean Top Panel. Look at that happiness. Ouch.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_CITIES_1">
			<Text>You're going to need a miracle to bring your cities up to the average.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>You'll never see the blue jeans coming.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Human is asking the AI for something -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>God has given me this land. Who are you to take it away?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>My apologies, I didn't realise.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>The riches of a rich man are his strength, but the need of the poor is what destroys them. Let us be rich men.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Riches taken by wrong-doing do no good, but doing what is right and good saves from death.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Attacked by Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Death to the unbelievers!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>The angel of death shall breathe in your face, and your heart shall beat but once, and forever grow still.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>You sadden me with your idolatery of war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>Well played, brother.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declaring War on Human - Strong and Weak also include the default response sets-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>When the storm passes, the sinful man is no more, but the man who is right with God has a place to stand forever. Remember this in the days that are to come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>Those who are right with God will never be shaken, but the sinful will not live in the land. Take heart that the faithful will be spared.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>The unbelievers shall be smote with righteousness and justice. This is my judgement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_2">
			<Text>I am the sword of fire which gardeth the garden of the Lord. All those idolaters who would defile His majesty will know my infernal blade.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>You have become vulnerable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>Yahweh protects me, I have no need to fear the coming battle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>Here in Israel, we have a great tradition of murdering our brothers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_DOW_BETRAYAL_2">
			<Text>God told me to.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>There shall be peace when the dove is seen flying over your grave.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_BAD_1">
			<Text>The foolish shall be destroyed by their own mouths.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ISRAEL_MOD_LS_SOLOMON_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Mazel tov.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						UA
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LS_EXODUS_SHORT">
			<Text>Promised Land</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LS_EXODUS">
			<Text>Gain [ICON_CULTURE] Culture from moving Settlers. Units have +2 [ICON_MOVEMENT] Movement and Sight until [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital is found.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						U1
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LS_SHOFET">
			<Text>Shofet</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_SHOFET">
			<Text>Gain [ICON_PEACE] Faith from kills.[NEWLINE]Heals at normal rate in neutral territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LS_SHOFET_TEXT">
			<Text>During the wandering (Exodus) period of Israelite history, Shofets were the de facto chiefs of the various Jewish tribes. In the Book of Judges, a cyclical pattern is given to show the need for the various judges: apostasy of the Israelite people, hardship brought on as punishment from God, crying out to the Lord for rescue. The judges were the successive individuals, each from a different tribe of Israel, chosen by God to rescue the people from their enemies and establish justice and the practice of the Torah amongst the Hebrews.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LS_SHOFET_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unlike the Warrior, which it replaces, the Shofet heals at a higher rate in neutral territory. Coupled with earning [ICON_PEACE] from kills, the Shofet is the ideal unit for clearing out barbarian encampments and escorting Settlers as they travel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LS_ISREALI_UA">
			<Text>Promised Lands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LS_ISREALI_UA_HELP">
			<Text>+2 [ICON_MOVES] Movement and Sight until Capital is found.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LS_SHOFET_LS">
			<Text>Border Defender</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LS_SHOFET_LS_HELP">
			<Text>Heals at normal rate in neutral territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!----------------------------------------------------------------
						U2
		------------------------------------------------------------------>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LS_YESHIVA">
			<Text>Yeshiva</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LS_YESHIVA_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science for every 2 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizens in the city.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Shares every third point of [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Scientist with other cities, which have Yeshiva.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LS_YESHIVA_TEXT">
			<Text>A Yeshiva is a Jewish institution that focuses on the study of traditional religious texts, primarily the Talmud and Torah study. Study is usually done through daily shiurim and in study pairs called chavrutas.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] The Geonic period takes its name from Gaon, the title bestowed on the heads of the three yeshivas in existence from the third to the thirteenth century. The Geonim acted as the principals of their individual yeshivot, and as spiritual leaders and high judges for the wider communities tied to them. The yeshiva conducted all official business in the name of its Gaon, and all correspondence to or from the yeshiva was addressed directly to the Gaon.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LS_YESHIVA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unlike the Library, which it replaces, the Yeshiva increases the speed at which your empire generates [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] by sharing a third of Great Scientist points between all cities containing a Yeshiva. With enough Yeshiva, Israel can generate more Great People than anyone else. Look for Policies and Technologies that augment your Great People.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>