<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Description tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKYTOWER">
			<Text>The Sky Tower</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Help tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_SKYTOWER_HELP">
			<Text>-15% [ICON_HAPPINESS_4] Unhappiness from [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizens in non-occupied Cities[NEWLINE]Free Broadcast tower in the city it was constructed in.[NEWLINE] +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold for every 4 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizens in the city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Quote tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_SKYTOWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE]"If it would not look too much like showing off, I would tell the reader where New Zealand is."[NEWLINE] - Mark Twain[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pedia tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_SKYTOWER_PEDIA">
			<Text>The Sky Tower is the most prominent and instantly recognisable feature of the skyline of Auckland, New Zealand. It is visible from most parts of the city, and greets tourists to New Zealand as their plane approaches the runway, giving a broadside view of the Auckland CBD (Central Business District). It took two and a half years to build, and was completed in March 1997. This was six months ahead of schedule. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] The tower is part of the SkyCity complex, and features a Casino, several observation decks and a rotating resteraunt, which rotates at 6 degrees every minute, giving a complete view of Auckland once every hour. The tower also features a SkyWalk and SkyJump, where people can walk on the exterior ledge of the observation deck, while connected to harnasses, or Bungy Jump off the edge. Above these commercial uses, the tower serves as a FM Radio and Digital Television transmitter.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]At the base of the tower there are thousands of LED lights which are used to illuminate the tower. These are coloured differently to celebrate different events. For example, the tower is Bright Green on Saint Patricks day, and Red and Gold on Chinese New Year. It also promotes several causes, such as being Pink for Breast Cancer awareness month and Blue and Green for the Starship Childrens Hospital. </Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
