<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Description tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHEOMSEONGDAE">
			<Text>Cheomseongdae</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Help tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CHEOMSEONGDAE_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_SCIENCE] Science for every 3 [ICON_CITIZENS] Citizens in this city.[NEWLINE][COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]Masonry is also required[ENDCOLOR]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Quote tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CHEOMSEONGDAE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE]"Do not try to cover the whole sky with the palm of your hand". "[NEWLINE] - Korean Proverb[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pedia tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CHEOMSEONGDAE_PEDIA">
			<Text>Cheomseongdae is one of the oldest Astronomical structures on Earth, and the oldest in East Asia. It is located in Gyenongju, South Korea, and dates back to the 7th century CE. It was built during the reign of Queen Seondeok in the capital of the time, before it was moved to Seoul. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]According to some scholars, Cheomseongdae is not at all an astronomical facility, and instead served a function which today falls under the category of Astrology. At the time, however, the two fields were vitrually indistinguishable. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TEMPLO">
			<Text>Templo Mayor</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Help tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_TEMPLO_HELP">
			<Text>+15% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when constructing Wonders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Quote tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_TEMPLO_QUOTE">
			<Text>
				[NEWLINE]" All things of the Earth have an end and in the midst of the most joyous lives, the breath falters, they fall, they sink into the ground."[NEWLINE]- King Nezahualcoyotl.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pedia tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_TEMPLO_PEDIA">
			<Text>Templo Mayor was a large double temple done in the iconic Mesoamerican Stepped Pyramid style located in the Aztec capital of Tenochtitlan, modern day Mexico City. It was dedicated to two gods of the Aztec pantheon, Huitzilopochtli, the god of war, and Tlaloc, the god of rain and agriculture. The dedication to two gods was the reason for the temple having twin shrines and staircases, each one dedicated to a seperate god. It is widely believed that the Shrine of Tlaloc was painted blue, while Huitzilopochtli's shrine was red. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] The exact date of the first construction is not known, although most estimates put this to be sometime in the early 14th century. Each sucessive generation of Aztec citizens increased the size of Templo Mayor by building around the previous building. This is believed to have happened about six times across the life of the temple. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Following the Spanish conquest of the Aztecs by Hernan Cortez in 1521, Templo Mayor was destroyed, along with the rest of Tenochtitlan. The Spanish filled in the lake upon which the city was built, and covered the site in soil. They then built the modern day city of Mexico on the site. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Description tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOME">
			<Text>Dome of the Rock</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Help tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_DOME_HELP">
			<Text>Free Great Prophet</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Quote tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_DOME_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE]“No city in the world, not even Athens or Rome, ever played as great a role in the life of a nation for so long a time as Jerusalem."[NEWLINE] - David Ben-Gurion[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pedia tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_DOME_PEDIA">
			<Text>Dome of the Rock is a colourful Islamic shrine located atop Temple Mount in the center of the city of Jerusalem. It was completed in 691 CE on the site of the Second Jewish Temple, and restored several times since. It is centered around the 'foundation rock', a rock upon which it is believed that the prophet Muhammed ascended to heaven. Interestingly, the Dome of the Rock was constructed not as a mosque, but rather as a shrine for Muslim pilgrims venturing to the Holy Land. Below the Dome of the Rock are a series of caverns which run throughout Jerusalem. These can be accessed via a crack in the Foundation Rock which leads to a cave known as the 'Well of Souls', a term made popular by the movie Indiana Jones and the Raiders of the Lost Ark. The exterior of the dome is made from porcelain and is octagonal in shape. Predominantly blue in the upper sections, islamic motifs cover the entire section. The dome is wooden with a 20 metre diameter and gold in colour.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BANAUE">
			<Text>Banaue Rice Terraces</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Help tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_BANAUE_HELP">
			<Text>Provides +2 [ICON_RES_RICE] Rice resources. City must be built on a hill.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Quote tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_BANAUE_QUOTE">
			<Text>
				[NEWLINE]"From wonder into wonder existence opens."[NEWLINE] - Lao Tzu[NEWLINE]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pedia tags -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_BANAUE_PEDIA">
			<Text>5000 feet above the sea, covering approximately 4000 square miles of Ifagao mountainside, sits the Banaue Rice Terraces. The terraces are about 2000 years old, built by the ancient indigenous Ifugao, and is still fed today by an ancient irrigation system using the rainforests above. It is common belief that the ancient terraces were built with minimal equipment and mostly by hand. It is said that putting the steps to travel the terraces end to end, they would encircle half the Equator of our Earth. The Ifugao culture is dominated by the use of rice, introducing the many rice culture feasts to the young and agricultural rites from the cultivation to consumption of rice.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Today the terraces are still in use, farming rice and vegetables to the Ifugao. However, more of the Ifugao find farming unappealing to other industries. This has resulted in a slow erosion of the site - the steps having been most affected - and the greater need for care of the site. In 2010 a greater problem emerged - drought - which caused the terraces to dry up entirely by March.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
