<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 17/11/2012 12:43:21 -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>You will face me on the battlefield!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>You have insulted us for the last time. This means war!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>You are a scourge to the Yup'iks which we will no longer tolerate!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Oooh, I knew you were nothing but trouble!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>Ridiculous! I have not lost!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>Very well...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Camai! I have heard whispers of you through the forests. Finally, do I get to meet you. I am Apanuugpak, Winter Warrior of the mighty Yup'ik Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Camai! The Yup'ik people greets you, Stranger! I am Apanuugpak!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>Camai! Greetings, Stranger! I am Apanuugpak, mighty leader of the Yup'iks! Let us feast to celebrate this grand occasion!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Ah, welcome back. The Yup'iks are always happy to entertain friends.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Camai! We of the Yup'ik Empire great you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Do you wish to attack the mighty Yup'iks? Your armies seems to indicate this. Pull them back before it's too late.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Are you like all the others? Respect the rights of the Yup'iks before this leads to war!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Even the mighty will stumble. Might I ask a good friend for help?</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
	<Language_FR_FR>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>Rendez-vous sur le champs de bataille!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>Vous nous avez suffisamment insultés, cela signifie la guerre!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>Vous êtes une plaie pour les Yup'iks, et cela ne peut plus être toléré!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Je savais bien que vous ne seriez qu'une source de problèmes pour nous!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>C'est ridicule, je n'ai pas perdu!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>Trés bien...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Camai! Des caravannes de marchands m'ont dit bien des choses à votre sujet. Je vous rencontre enfin. Je suis Apanuugpak, Guerrier de l'Hiver de l'empire des Yup'iks!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Camai! Les Yup'iks vous saluent étranger! Je suis Apanuugpak!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>Camai! Salutation étranger! Je suis Apanuugpak, grand Guerrier de l'Hiver de l'Empire Yup'ik! Célèbrons cette rencontre!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Ah, encore vous? Les Yup'iks sont toujours ravis de parler à des amis.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>L'empire des Yup'iks vous salue.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Vous avez l'intention de nous attaquer? C'est ce que semblent indiquer les récents mouvements de troupes à nos frontières. Retirez-les avant qu'il ne soit trop tard.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Votre expansion telle la gangraine nous inquiète! Modérez votre expansion ou vous allez le regretter!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_APANUUGPAK_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Les temps sont durs. Puis-je solliciter l'aide d'un bon ami?</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_FR_FR>
</GameData>